Shuvozit Ghose

८ +1-431-554-2105 **▼**shuvozit,ghose@gmail.com **③** /shuvozitghose.github.io/ **♀** Canada in /shuvozitghose/ O/ShuvozitGhose

Summary

An ML engineer/ data scientist with 4+ years of hands-on experience in machine learning research and development. My expertise encompasses a profound understanding of key machine learning concepts, coupled with a comprehensive grasp of data preprocessing, model training, and effective deployment strategies. My practical work has spanned diverse machine learning techniques, including prompt learning, domain adaptation, meta-learning, generative adversarial networks, self-supervised learning, and few-shot learning etc.

Education

Master of Science — ML Specialization DGPA: 4.20/4.50

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023 University of Manitoba, Canada

Bachelor of Technology — Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

DGPA: 8.87/10.

West Bengal University of Technology, India

Technical Skills -

 $Python \mid Pytorch \mid Git \mid Azure\ Data\ Factory \mid Apche\ Pyspark \mid Azure\ Databricks \mid Azure\ Synapse\ Analytics \mid$ $Microsoft\ Power\ BI\ |\ Docker\ |\ Kubernetes\ |\ CI/CD\ |\ Tensorflow\ |\ OpenCV\ |\ SQL\ |\ Numpy\ |\ Panda\ |\ Java\ |$ $C + + \mid C$

Professional Experience

Graduate Teaching Assistant | University of Manitoba

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023 | Canada

- Conducted lab for undergraduate students for course Comp 2140 data structure and algorithm using Java.
- Graded assignments and code in Python for the course COMP 4360 machine learning and provided constructive feedback to students.
- Graded code in Java, C++, and Javascript for the course COMP 2150 object orientation and provided constructive feedback to students.
- Graded projects in Java using Android Studio for the course COMP 3350 Software Engineering and provided constructive feedback to students.
- Graded code in processing for the course COMP 3490 Computer Graphics I and provided constructive feedback to students.

Graduate Research Assistant | University of Manitoba

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023 | Canada

- Developed a Pretrained Point Cloud to Image Translation Network for CLIP-based point cloud recognition using Python and Pytorch.
- Introduced a novel viewpoint adapter for a prompt-based point cloud recognition system.
- Developed a novel few-shot meta-episodic learning framework for CLIP-based point cloud classification.
- Computed inference using PyTorch on both CPU and GPU running CUDA 11.2 (@Acc > 85%).

Research Intern | University of Surrey

June 2020 – Mar 2021 | UK

- Developed a multi-stage joint visual semantic reasoning decoder for text recognition using Python and Pytorch.
- Developed a Writer-Adaptive Handwritten Text Recognition system using meta-learning.

Notable Projects -

2021 Tokyo Olympic data analytics in Microsoft Azure

- Extracted raw Tokyo Olympic data from GitHub using Azure Data Factory.
- Transformed raw data using Apache Pysparck in Azure Databricks and stored in Azure Data Lake Gen 2.
- Loaded transformed data in Azure Synapse Analytics and Visualized the results using Microsoft Power BI.

Achievements

- 1. Awarded University of Manitoba Graduate Fellowship (UMGF) at the University of Manitoba 2022-2023.
- 2. Awarded International Graduate Student Entrance Scholarship (IGSES) at the University of Manitoba 2021.
- 3. Got NPTEL Elite Certification in Deep Learning for Visual Computing, 2018.

Publications ————————————————————————————————————			
C7	Joint Visual Semantic Reasoning: Multi-Stage Decoder for Text Recognition Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Aneeshan Sain, Amandeep Kumar, Shuvozit Ghose, Pinaki Nath Chohury, Yi-Zhe Song		Oct 2021
C6	IEEE Conference on International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) MetaHTR: Towards Writer-Adaptive Handwritten Text Recognition Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose, Amandeep Kumar, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Anees Sain, Yi-Zhe Song IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)		June 2021
C5	Modeling Extent-of-Texture Information for Ground Terrain Recognition Shuvozit Ghose, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Partha Pratim Roy, Umapada Pal IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)	<u>PDF</u>	Sept 2020
C4	UDBNET: Unsupervised Document Binarization Network via Adversarial Game Amandeep Kumar*, Shuvozit Ghose*, Pinaki Nath Chowdhury, Partha Pratim Roy, Umap Pal IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)	oada <u>PDF</u>	Sept 2020
C3	Fractional Local Neighborhood Intensity Pattern for Image Retrieval using Genetic gorithm Shuvozit Ghose, Abhirup Das, Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Partha Pratim Roy Multimedia Tools and Applications	: Al - <u>PDF</u>	Sept 2020
C2	A Deep One-Shot Network for Query-based Logo Retrieval Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Ankan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose , Abhirup Das, Partha Pratim Umapada Pal) Pattern Recognition	Roy, <u>PDF</u>	July 2019
C1	User Constrained Thumbnail Generation Using Adaptive Convolutions Perla Sai Raj Kishore, Ayan Kumar Bhunia, Shuvozit Ghose , Partha Pratim Roy International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)	<u>PDF</u>	May 2019